

Balaji J

Email: balaii93bobby@gmail.com

Phone: 9585840473

Career Objective :-

With my utmost interest in technology, constantly upskilling myself with newer technologies to be on par with the current trend. Thrive to share ideas and technical expertise with fellow brethren to help make a change in the world. Trying newer and different ideas to make a breakthrough in my career.

Job Responsibilities:

Installation & Configuration of Netgear Devices

· Configuring reservations for important resources in DHCP.

Creating user accounts & mail boxes for new users.

· Configuring LAN/Wireless Networks at client machines.

Hardware troubleshooting.

Troubleshooting of PC's, & Network connections.

Technical Skills:

• **Protocols**: HTTPS, HTTP, DNS, DHCP, FTP, SSH, SMTP, IMAP, TCP/IP and UDP.

Applications: MS office, Wire-shark.

Remote tools: Putty, SSH, Any Desk, Team Viewer and Telnet.

• AWS : IAM, S3, Cloud Watch, VPC, EBS, Cloud Trail, EC2, Glacier, ELB, AMI, Snapshots, RDS

,Route53.

· Language : Python

Professional Experience:-

SVL Vidhya Lakshmi Real Estate	6 Years (2013-2019)	Business Development Executive
Dreamzone school of creative studies	1 Year (2019-2020)	Business Development Executive
Colorhomes Developer Pvt Ltd	1 Year (2020-2021)	Customer Support Executive
Brightchamps Tech Pvt Ltd	6 Months (2021)	Coding Educator
Concentrix Technologies India Pvt Ltd	9 Months (JAN 2022 - SEP 2022)	Technical support Engineer

Hardware Skills:-

- System Assembling and Disassembling.
- System Utilities and Troubleshooting.

Hands On Experience:

Networking

High technical knowledge of network configuration:

- Netgear routers and switches, Router redistribution
- Adept with routing protocols:

RIP, BGP, OSPF, EIGRP

· Vast knowledge of Layer 2 technology:

VLAN, VTP, Spanning-tree

- Expertise in Layer 3 switching:
- Proficient in Network management including:
- Efficient in utilizing operating systems:

Mac OSX, Windows

- Superb in utilizing wireless equipment:
- · Wide range of capabilities to:

Utilize network monitoring tools,

Troubleshoot network systems and applications,

Interpret PC hardware and software concepts

Amazon Web Services:-

- Expertise in Amazon AWS Cloud Administration which includes services like: EC2, S3, EBS, VPC, ELB,
 AMI, RDS, IAM, Route 53, Auto scaling.
- CloudFront, Cloud Watch, Cloud Trail, Cloud Formation, Security Groups.
- Installing and configuring applications on AWS **EC2** Instances.
- · Creating IAM Users and Groups and Maintaining the user Access management and Permissions.
- Managing AWS instances Via Monitoring tool and action the alerts accordingly.
- Configured and managed security groups and VPC.
- · Creating **Elastic IPs** attaching and detaching to instances as per Users request.
- · Create and configure **S3** bucket with restricted policies.

Devops:-

Basic Knowledge on CI/CD pipeline using **Jenkins**.

Training:

- Trained on CCNA from Network Rhinos
- Certified on AWS Cloud Practitioner

Education Oualifications:

B.sc Computer science 3rd Year Alagappa University in Distance education.

Personal Profile:-

Hobbies : Watching Movies and Traveling

Permanent Address : No 1, 1st Street Balaji Nagar, Kolapakkam, Chennai-128

Languages Known : English, Tamil and Telugu

Declaration:

I hereby declare that all the information provided above is true and the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Chennai **Signature**: Balaji J